For me, it [music] has to be Lamine
Yamal.
I feel like the Ballon d'Or winner has
to come from [music] the team that won
the World Cup. Spain won the World Cup,
and Lamine wasn't at his best at the
World Cup. We saw that, but he was still
>> [music]
>> an important part of the team that won.
And it was a more mature performance
from Lamine. He wasn't necessarily
trying to take on too many people. He
[music] did what was needed to be done
to win the World Cup. But generally
speaking, Lamine Yamal is a player that
just exudes joy. Why do we watch
football, people? To enjoy ourselves, to
feel alive, to scream out in joy. Wow,
what was that? And Lamine makes us feel
that. Look at his numbers. His numbers
are brilliant as well. For a winger, for
a 19-year-old winger. He's not a
striker. He's a winger. But take a look
at these goals and assists. That's
That's a huge number of goals and
assists for a 19-year-old winger. But
what about the
maybe the key aspect of being a winger,
and also being a winger in a team that
plays up against low blocks like
Barcelona, like Spain. He needs to do
successful dribbles. And he's completed
more successful dribbles than any other
player in Europe this season. By
absolute miles. He's the best at that.
He is a player that just brings joy,
enjoyment, delight to everybody that
watches. He has won trophies. He has
been a key part of those trophies. He
got one yellow card in La Liga last
season, by the way, getting kicked all
over the place. Only one yellow card, if
we're talking about fair play as well. I
think he is an the outstanding candidate
to win the Ballon d'Or this year.
>> Case made. Nico,
how you feeling?
>> I I I think uh he has a strong case when
you
ask yourself, are his performances in La
Liga
and Copa del Rey
Oh, well, they didn't win Copa del Rey,
but excuse me.
>> Supercopa.
>> In Supercopa. Are his performances
domestically enough to win
Ballon d'Or? I know that we're searching
for something
greater here, right? Because Barcelona
definitely are destined for something
greater.
>> Barcelona's top scorer
>> Right.
>> in La Liga.
>> Florian Albert won the 1967
Ballon d'Or because I think it was
Ferenc Yeah, Ferenc Váradi won the
Hungarian league and he was
extraordinary in the Hungarian league.
>> It was a strong league back then.
>> It was a strong It was a strong league
back then and and and Hungary was a
powerhouse of of football or at least
coming off of their golden era.
I don't think and this is goes back to
the whole Messi-Ronaldo debate that
these two were going neck and neck
winning Champions Leagues and
I don't think we should undermine the
achievement of a league and I understand
that today in modern football leagues
tend to be a little bit top-heavy, maybe
top two-heavy like La Liga, like the
Bundesliga, and like so many other
around Europe save the Premier League. I
could even make an argument that the
Premier League has been top-heavy for
the last 8 years, right? So, I don't
think
England is specifically excluded from
all of this.
A top league performance
should be recognized as a Ballon d'Or
worthy
performance throughout an entire year.
That's why I don't think Kane in the
Bundesliga should be undermined
whatsoever.
I think people I think people do do it.
I mean, look at the comments. I do I do
think people say
Freiburg and Freiburg was actually not
that bad. But but like you know like
some How league
Hamburg and all this stuff.
>> It's it's a daft comment because it's
like saying, "Well, yeah, you know he
did that, but you know, he wasn't
playing Barcelona and Atleti every
week." Well, you can't, can you? You do
have to play lesser teams. That's the
whole purpose of a league. That's why
you have promotion and relegation. So, I
I dismiss those comments.
>> Yeah, but I My point is that
we shouldn't not recognize somebody as a
worthy Ballon d'Or candidate because he
just won the league.
>> Mhm.
Equally equally
you said you think the winner should
come from the team that won the World
Cup.
>> Yeah.
>> That would change the Ballon d'Or
completely because then you would only
have a player who's won the World Cup
each time the World Cup is won.
Is that what you're saying?
>> years.
>> You think so?
Whoever wins the World Cup only a player
who's won the World Cup will win the
Ballon d'Or.
>> I would say if there's an out sta- if
there's an outstanding [clears throat]
team, you know, sometimes people can win
the World Cup in different ways.
>> Yeah.
>> No, no, I was just saying
>> What you actually said.
>> the clearly the best team at that
tournament by miles.
>> I'm I'm not disputing that. You said you
said the Ballon d'Or winner should come
from the team that won the World Cup.
>> like it probably should, yeah.
>> But every four years
>> Probably.
>> It holds more weight than any other
trophy that anybody else could have won
in the ballot.
>> The last time that a Ballon d'Or winner
uh coming off of a World Cup year didn't
win it was in 2015 when Messi won it and
Germany won the World Cup. Messi did get
to the final.
>> And won best player.
>> Listen, I think you know is a a
fantastic player. Agree with all those
things. But he didn't have a great World
Cup by any stretch of the imagination.
Because his well his numbers tell you
don't need
>> He was instrumental in the goal that was
scored in the final.
>> Well, how come he has zero assists?
Zero.
You told us what a great
>> pre-assist in the World Cup final.
>> Key pre-assist.
>> Key pre-assist to brag about.
That he dragged a bunch of he dragged he
absorbed the mark. It's like he forgets
to mention that Argentina was down to 10
men. Um
>> Nico, who gave the ball to Maradona when
he scored the hand of God goal?
>> Yeah. Not the hand of God goal, the
other one though.
>> Yeah, he says with an assist like that,
how can you fail to score?
>> You're the one bringing up assists.
>> No, no,
I'm ridiculing your pre-assist.
>> Uh
>> [laughter]
>> Luka Modrić I mean to correct myself.
>> agree with me though, Nico?
>> In 2019 won the Ballon d'Or.
>> Nico?
>> 18, yes.
>> 18, yeah, yeah.
>> Do you agree that he didn't have by his
standards a great World Cup? Look at
look at the bare numbers.
>> everything you said
>> He says it as well. He admits it. He
says
>> So on that on that on that basis that
you say that he had a modest World Cup.
I think that's a
a way of presenting the situation.
>> says it. He himself says it.
>> If he was 100% he would have had a
wildly different World Cup.
>> Okay. I'm also going to double down on
it must be a World Cup winner. So had
Rodri had a really
Sorry. Say Rodri had a good season.
>> Mhm.
>> And they won the World Cup, you'd have
given it to Rodri.
>> Maybe.
>> Probably.
>> If like City would have won the Ballon
d'Or and Rodri
>> Not enough. Not enough. Not enough for
me because he he he didn't have by his
standards because he was injured. It was
clearly bothering him the injury going
into it. I feel so sorry for him because
the numbers, that's what he's there for.
He doesn't score enough goals
for his national team. We saw that at
Wembley the other night as well. Scores
one beautiful goal.
Chance is there.
Listen. We'll be debating how many
Ballon d'Ors he wins in the future.
I just don't think he deserves it this
year up against Kane's numbers and
performances.
>> Doesn't it make it this much more
exciting though that we don't know who
could win Ballon d'Or in a month's time?
It just like it keeps us on our toes.
It's it's something to look forward to,
right? You can make cases for why people
should win and
why they shouldn't win. And I don't know
which ones
>> I but I don't think again, I think we
should explain the nuance. I don't think
Lamine Yamal is undeserving, Jeff.
>> Yeah.
Not at all, but I don't think he's
deserving as Harry Kane.
>> Okay, fair.
>> You agree with me?
We'll find out.
>> You will We'll find out, but if if
Lamine Yamal walks up to the podium with
a Ballon d'Or in his hand
>> Won't be surprised.
>> I I I couldn't say
>> Of course it's not. It's not It's not
outlandish, Joe.
>> Like let I I would wonder what our
threshold is. Up until what candidate
would we think it's an outrage? You
think if Messi won the Ballon d'Or would
it be an outrage?
>> See, I wouldn't be
>> Is that our threshold?
>> No.
>> Yeah. I was looking I was looking at
Phil's list and I was thinking
Same I looked at my list. What Why have
you got Michael Olise so low? Why have
you got so-and-so so high?" Cuz you can
make cases for all of them.
>> Thanks for watching this video from
Morning Footy for all news and insights
regarding leagues around the world like
EFL, Serie A, and all UEFA competitions
both men's and women's. Don't forget to
sign up for Paramount Plus.